[Music]
hi and welcome back to the channel
it's halloween tomorrow so because of
that we thought we'd do
salt and straws the great candy copia
what is it
it's a bourbon butterscotch ice cream
with whoppers snickers heath bars
and reese's peanut butter cups all
folded in
all of that so that there's none left
for the trick or treaters so if you want
to see how it's made stick around and
we'll show you
let's get started with the salt and
straw base shall we in your pan add 45
grams of corn syrup and 470 milliliters
of milk then stir that in well and add
your 90 grams of sugar which also has
your one and a half grams of xanthan gum
mixed in and your 45 grams of skim milk
powder
mix that all in well until the sugar is
dissolved then turn off the heat and add
your 470 milliliters of cream chill that
down for four hours or more
[Music]
next it's time to make the butterscotch
first take your 50 grams of light brown
sugar
your 15 grams of granulated sugar and 15
grams of corn syrup along with your 30
grams of bourbon and put them all in a
pan mix it all up until all the sugars
look slightly wet then fire that heat up
get that puppy to a gentle smoke point
without stirring and then take it off
the heat
add your 60 grams of heavy cream
5 grams of butter a small splash of
vanilla and a small pinch of salt stir
that all in well store it at room
temperature until your base is chilled
[Applause]
[Music]
when your base is chilled
and before churning add the butterscotch
sauce to your chilled base and mix it in
well this takes a while doing it this
way so just keep on stirring and it will
all disappear then add it to your ice
cream machine and churn it away
whilst the ice cream is churning it's
time to chop up your add-ins so take
your stickers heath bars reese's cups
and whoppers and chop them all up nice
and small
[Music]
[Applause]
when your ice cream reaches soft serve
consistency remove it from your machine
and fold in all the sweetie goodness
freeze it for a few hours and we'll come
back and see what it looks like
[Music]
[Applause]
look at that
amazing tub the witch up there dropping
all the candies down into the ice cream
in the uk getting
whoppers and heath bars
is a nightmare i did manage to get
whoppers and that was when we went to
bath actually so you can see that on our
social media i'll put links down below
there was an american or worldwide
actually sweet shop and they happen to
have those and they cost a fortune for a
bag so i couldn't get the heath bars and
that's why i made them in last week's
video
so now that we've got our freezer let's
get some scooped up and see what it
looks like
[Music]
[Applause]
okay
so let's just see what this tastes like
i mean first off there's loads of stuff
in there
but that side the ice cream smells quite
nice
[Music]
now i usually love add-ins
but these are a bit dry really
the ice cream is really good
kind of tastes like weather's originals
it's a nice butterscotch caramelly kind
of taste it's a good texture
i'm not
i'm not sure about the add-ins there's a
lot of them the snickers goes rock hard
whoppers now
controversy and all that
whoppers versus maltesers they're
slightly different
whoppers have or appear to have slightly
more multi-flavor than maltesers
but they taste like
so
you know i would use more deezers every
day of the week
snickers yeah like i said it goes rock
hard the heath bar actually works quite
well although it does go hard it goes
soft and and melts in your mouth the
moment they're in there
the peanut butter cups
i love peanut butter my wife doesn't
like peanut butter so i when i tub this
up half of it didn't have it in
but it needs something else it needs
like a fudge swirl or a sauce or
something just to break it up and
probably less add-ins but i mean you
know it's it's a flavor for halloween
it's designed just to throw everything
in there for a bit of fun and they'll
remove it when halloween is over
it is just ice cream should be about fun
so i guess when you look at it like that
this is a great one texture really nice
flavor really nice so give this one a
try if you like all the add-ins thanks
very much for watching don't forget to
like and subscribe as i said in a
previous video we're doing some more
asmr videos next week we're going to do
another one so
stick around and
thanks for watching
[Music]